David Robles

Contact

Phone: (415) 515-4764 Email: drobles@gmail.com Twitter: @davidrobles

Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/drobles

Summary

Software Engineer with a strong focus on tackling engineering challenges, writing quality software and with strong grasp of software architecture, advanced software engineering principles and design patterns.

I recently completed an MSc and PhD in Computer Science from the University of Essex, where I conducted research focused on Reinforcement Learning, Simulation-Based Search, Evolutionary Algorithms and Games. During this time I was also a Teaching Assistant in several courses in programming and web application development.

I'm currently a Software Engineer at dotloop, where I work primarily as a Java backend developer responsible for designing and implementing new features and RESTful APIs. In my free time, I love programming in Ruby, Rails, Python, and more recently I've been diving into functional programming.

EDUCATION

PhD Computer Science

University of Essex Colchester, United Kingdom 2009 - 2013

Thesis: "Simulation-Based Search and Learning in Games"

MSc Computer Science

University of Essex Colchester, United Kingdom 2007 - 2008

Software engineering theme, passed with distinction.

BSc Information Systems Engineering

Institute of Technology and Higher Education of Monterrey Hermosillo, Mexico 2001 - $2006\,$

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

DotLoop San Francisco, CA January 2013 - Present

- Java backend developer.
- Design and implementation of new features and RESTful APIs in Spring MVC.

Teaching Assistant

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2009 - March 2012

Preparation, marking and teaching of classes and laboratories for the following undergraduate and postgraduate courses:

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2011.

CE320 - Large Scale Software Scale Systems and Extreme Programming, Autumn 2011.

CE218 - Computer Game Programming, Spring 2011.

 $\mathrm{CE}152$ - Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2011.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2010.

CE212 - Web Application Programming, Spring 2010.

CE112 - Procedural and Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2010.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2009.

Systems Administrator

Camisa Development Group Hermosillo, Mexico March 2006 - May 2007

Network Administrator, Windows Server 2003, Active Directory, VPN, CRM Software, Sage SalesLogix.

SKILLS

Programming languages: Java, Ruby, Python, PHP, C.

Web Development: Ruby on Rails, Spring MVC, JSP/Servlets, JavaScript, CSS.

Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Mockito. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL. Cloud: Amazon EC2/S3, Heroku. Version Control: Git, SVN. OS: Unix/Linux, Mac OS X.

AWARDS Scholarship for MSc and PhD Computer Science degrees from the National Council of

Science and Technology of Mexico.

CERTIFICATIONS Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), February 2006.

Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA), May 2007.